Finding Aid for the Kenneth Macgowan Papers LSC.0887
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Special Projects
  - Anthropology
    - Anthropology - Correspondence Pertaining to Kenneth Macgowan's Book, Early Man In The New World
      - Correspondence... re Early man in the new world. continued. v.p., 1945-1961.; 84 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). Arranged alphabetically, E - L. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Everett, Glenn D., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Field, Henry., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Flint, Richard Foster., 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Godfrey, Marian Angell Mrs. William S. Godfrey., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Gray, Hilda., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Gross, Hugo., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Hagar, Elizabeth., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Harrington, M.R., 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Heizer, Robert F., 11 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Hencken, Hugh., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Hibben, Frank C., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Holland, Neil., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Holt, Henry and Company, Incorporated, publishers., 9 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Hooten, Earnest Albert., 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Howells, W.W., 13 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Hubble, Grace., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Irwin, Constance., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Jepsen, Glenn L., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Johnson, Frederick., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Kroeber, A.L., 4 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Krogman, Wilton Marion., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Leighton, M.M., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Longstreet, Stephen., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Lux, Florence., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence... re Early man in the new world. continued. v.p., 1945-1961.; 103 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Included are unidentified, undated leaves, fragments, and address lists. Arranged alphabetically, M - Z.
        - McCown, Theodore D., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - MacCurdy, George Grant., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Incorporated., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - McGregor, James H., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Mangelsdorf, Paul C., 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Moss, John Hall., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Mostny, Greta., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Movius, Hallam L., 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Nelson, N.C., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Peabody museum of archaeology and ethnology., 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Ray, Cyrus N., 5 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Richardson, Francis B., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Richert, Sue., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Roberts, Frank H.H. Jr., 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Roberts, Walter Orr., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Romey, Alfred S., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Sachs, Curt., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Satterthwaite, Linton., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Seidenberg, Roderick., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Smithsonian Institution. United States National Museum., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Spinden, Herbert J., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Standley, Paul C., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Stubbs, Stanley A., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Styson, Arthur., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Taylor, Griffith., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Texas agricultural experiment station. Agricultural and mechanical college of Texas. College station, Texas., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Texas memorial museum., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Thompson, Jay., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Vaillant, Sue Mrs. George Vaillant., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Vision, Incorporated. New York., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - The Viking Fund, Incorporated. New York., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Waller, A.E., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Weatherwax, Paul., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Webster, Doris Mrs. Samuel Webster., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Weitzner, Bella., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Whitman, Edmund S., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Williams, Howel., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Wisner, Carl V. Jr., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Yorke, Gabriel S., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Unidentified correspondence re Early man in the new world. v.p., v.d.; 5 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Carbon copies of letters from Kenneth Macgowan to various persons re Early man in the new world, with no replies included, plus address lists, an invoice, and calling cards. v.p., v.d.; 17 items. Typescript (carbon), few printed. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Helmut De Terra re Early man in the new world. v.p., 1946-1950.; 26 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 9, Folder 4)
        Includes manuscript items and ephemera.
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Loren C. Eiseley re Early man in the new world. v.p., 1946-1948.; 10 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Harold S. Gladwin re Early man in the new world. California, 1945-1946.; 6 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Joseph Hester, re Early man in the new world. California, 1959-1960.; Approximately 100 items. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 9, Folder 7)
        Included are various leaves of manuscript with many corrections, and miscellaneous ephemera.
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Alex Krieger re Early man in the new world. v.p., 1947-1951.; 17 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 9, Folder 8)
        Included are 3 drawings and 1 article.
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and The Macmillan Company re Early man in the new world. New York, 1947-1953.; 23 items. Typescript (few carbon). (Box 9, Folder 9)
        Includes a few enclosures.
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Etienne Renaud re Early man in the new world. v.p., 1945-1950.; 14 items. Holograph and typescript (1 carbon). (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Carl Sauer re Early man in the new world. California, 1945-1948.; 28 items. Holograph and typescript (few carbon). (Box 9, Folder 11)
        Includes notes.
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and George Vaillant re Early man in the new world. v.p., 1940-1945.; 47 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 9, Folder 12)
        In additions are included 4 ephemera and 6 typescript leaves.
    - Anthropology - Correspondence, Manuscript Material, Photographs and Ephemera
      re Primitive Masks and the Book, Masks and Demons, Written By Kenneth Macgowan and Herman Rosse.
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and various persons re primitive masks. v.p., 1935-1955.; 34 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        Included are photographs and a few ephemera. Arranged alphabetically, A - G.
        - Altman, Ralph C., 9 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Bacon, Bessie Rilla., 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Barnes, Stanley N., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Beals, Ralph., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Blueyes, Jerry., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Brin, Arthur., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Carlebach, Julius, Incorporated, antiques and art objects., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Crown, Alfred., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Equitable investment corporation. Hollywood, California., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Gillmor, Frances., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Goldsmith, Keith., 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence... re primitive masks, continued. v.p., 1935-1955.; 34 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). Arranged alphabetically, H - M. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Harley, G.W., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Hendricks, Nameé Mrs. Walter A Hendricks., 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Hooper, T., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Ikeda, Toshiharu., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Jepson art institute. Los Angeles, California., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Lent, D. Geneva., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - The Library of Congress. Washington, D.C., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Lloyd-Morris, H., 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Mexican government travel bureau., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Montenegro, Roberto., 9 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - The museum of costume art. New York., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence... re primitive masks, continued. v.p., 1935-1955.; 78 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). Arranged alphabetically, N - Z. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - The nugget shop. Juneau, Alaska., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Oates, W.G.R., 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Parker, A.C., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Pepler, H.D.C., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Pepler, H.D.C., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Schweizer, H., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Scripps College. Claremont, California., 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Spinden, Herbert J., 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Tejeda, Antonio., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Thompson, W.J., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - The travelers. Marine agency corporation. New York., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Vandercook, John W., 11 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Virginia museum of fine arts. Richmond, Virginia., 10 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Williams, F.E., 4 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Wissler, Clark., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Yates, Helen Eva., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Unidentified correspondence re primitive masks, plus lists and one ink drawing. v.p., v.d.; 5 items. Typescript and holograph. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Carbon copies of letters from Kenneth Macgowan to various persons re primitive masks, with no replies included. [Los Angeles], v.d.; 9 items. Typescript (carbon). (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Francis Crowninshield re primitive masks. v.p., 1937-1938.; 29 items. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence between Kenneth Macgowan and Emil F. Meier re primitive masks. v.p., 1937-1940.; 18 items. Typescript (few carbon). (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous leaves of manuscript re primitive masks, probably re Masks and demons, written by Kenneth Macgowan and Herman Rosse. n.p., 35 leaves. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous leaves of manuscript re primitive masks... continued. n.p., n.d.; 66 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous notes and lists re various primitive masks. n.p., 26 items. Typescript. (Box 10, Folder 8)
        Includes notes on cards.
      - Article entitled Mexican masks by Roberto Montenegro, an essay and description by Xavier Villaurrutia and Ramon Mena (?). n.p., 12 leaves. Typescript (carbon). This article is fastened in a blue paper cover, and perhaps was used as research by Kenneth Macgowan. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Material re an exhibition of Kenneth Macgowan's collection of primitive masks at the Pasadena Institute of Art. Pasadena, 1945.; 8 items. (Box 10, Folder 10)
        Includes brochures and clippings.
      - Material re various exhibitions of Kenneth Macgowan's collection of primitive masks. v.p., 1940-1946.; 20 items. (Box 10, Folder 11)
        Includes brochures, clippings, mimeograph and other printed material.
      - Material re the exhibition of Kenneth Macgowan's collection of primitive masks at The Museum of Modern Art. New York, 1945.; 15 items. Mostly photographs. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous material re primitive masks. v.p., v.d.; 15 items. (Box 10, Folder 13)
        Including clippings, photographs, and one drawing.
      - Newspaper clippings, mainly reviews, of the book Masks and demons, written by Kenneth Macgowan and Herman Rosse. v.p., 1924.; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Photographs of movie sets using many of Kenneth Macgowan's primitive masks as background props such as wall hangings, etc. n.p., 23 items. Glossy, black and white, 3 × 5 and 8 × 10 sizes. Many duplicates are included, but the title of the movie is not indicated anywhere. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Photographs of masks, mounted on sheets of paper, captioned, probably illustrating the masks in the collection of Kenneth Macgowan. n.p., n.d.; Some of the photographs are missing from their captioned sheets. 56 photographs. 59 sheets. Photographs are glossy, black and white, size 2.5 × 4. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Material Pertaining to Various Special Projects With Which Kenneth Macgowan Was Involved; Arranged Alphabetically, A - Hollywood M
      - The American national theater and academy. New York, 1954-1963.; 29 items. Typescript and printed. (Box 11, Folder 1)
        Intercultural exchange service. Material re this group includes correspondence, reports, clippings, brochures, and publications of the organization.
      - Coordinator of inter-American affairs. v.p., 1941-1944.; 94 items. Holograph, typescript (much carbon), and printed items. (Box 11, Folder 2)
        Material re this office of the United States government includes correspondence, much of which pertains to inner workings of the office, records, reports, and lists, plus clippings, pamphlets, and various other ephemera.
      - Federal theater project. v.p., December 1938-July 1939.; 36 items. Typescript (mostly carbon), and a few printed items. (Box 11, Folder 3)
        Material re this project includes correspondence, records and reports, plus a few clippings, all items chronologically arranged.
      - Fulbright lecturship to the University of Bristol. v.p., 1952-1953.; 15 items. Holograph and typescript (mostly carbon), plus a few printed items. (Box 11, Folder 4)
        Material includes correspondence re application and possibilities for the grant, plus 2 pamphlets, plus 1 letter from Nelson Rockefeller. Material is arranged chronologically.
      - Golf. v.p., v.d.; Approximately 50 items. Printed material. (Box 11, Folder 5)
        Material includes clippings, score cards, rules, and articles about golf, a favorite sport of Kenneth Macgowan.
      - Golf. Printed booklets. v.p., v.d.; 3 items. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Hellenistic and Roman theaters. California, 1952-1953.; Approximately 20 items. Typescript (some carbon) and printed form maps. (Box 11, Folder 7)
        Material includes information on early theater in Greece in note form, plus maps and some correspondence.
      - Hollywood motion picture and television museum. v.p., 1959-1962.; Approximately 75 items. Holograph and typescript (much carbon), and some mimeograph and printed items. (Box 11, Folder 8)
        Material includes correspondence re the museum, plus reports, statements, and bulletins. All items are arranged chronologically. Correspondents include Sol Lesser, as well as others.
    - Material Pertaining to Various Special Projects With Which Kenneth Macgowan Was Involved; Arranged Alphabetically, Hollywood N - Z
      - Hollywood writers mobilization. v.p., 1944-1949.; 16 items. Typescript (some carbon) and a few printed items. (Box 12, Folder 1)
        Material includes correspondence re activities of the organization, a few clippings and other ephemera, plus one typescript and carbon about the group, written by Kenneth Macgowan. Items are chronologically arranged.
      - Latin American art exhibit. Pasadena art museum. Pasadena, 1943.; Approximately 60 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
        Material consists of lists of works and their owners, photographs, posters and ephemera. Items are arranged chronologically (Kenneth Macgowan served as director for this exhibit).
      - Latin American art exhibit. Pasadena art museum; continued. v.p., 1943.; 31 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
        Material consists of newspaper clippings and other ephemera about the exhibit, arranged chronologically.
      - Modern institute of art. v.p., 1947-1949.; Approximately 100 items. Holograph and typescript (much carbon). (Box 12, Folder 4)
        Material consists of correspondence, lists, records, reports, notes, and ephemera concerning the institute.
        - Altman, George., 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Arensberg, Walter., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Boardman, Dixon., 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Burke, Caroline., 3 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Dreyfuss, Henry., 3 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Fox, Milton., 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Green, Charles A., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Hayward, Leland., 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Huxley, Aldous., 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Loew, David L., 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Nelson, Donald M., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Price, Vincent L. Jr., 4 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Richter, Hans., 2 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Robinson, Edward G., 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Robinson, John Moore., 3 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Ross, Kenneth., 3 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Sauber, Sunny., 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Smith, Robert L., 3 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Tannenbaum, David., 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Warriner, Jean., 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified correspondence, drafts and carbon copies of letters re the Modern Institute of Art, Beverly Hills, California. v.p., v.d.; 6 items. Holograph and typescript (carbon). (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous lists, financial records, notes, reports, and other papers re the Modern Institute of Art, Beverly Hills, California. Beverly Hills, 1949.; Approximately 30 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Ephemera re the Modern Institute of Art, Beverly Hills, California. v.p., 1949.; 17 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
        Includes clippings and mailers and a mimeograph sheet.
      - Opportunity fellowships.v.p., 1954-1961.; 20 items. Typescript (mostly carbon) and some printed items. (Box 12, Folder 5)
        The material includes some correspondence, and a number of lists and printed items re the fellowships.
      - Society of cinematologists. v.p., 1960-1962.; 40 items. Typescript (some carbon), and various printed material. (Box 12, Folder 6)
        Material includes correspondence and ephemera, chronologically arranged.
      - Stanford conference on the humanities. California, 1945.; 19 items. (Box 12, Folder 7)
        Material primarily consists of typed notes, plus 1 booklet.
      - Travel. v.p., v.d.; Approximately 50 items. (Box 12, Folder 8)
        Material mainly consists of printed ephemera, with a few letters included.
      - United States information agency. Special packet on the American theater. v.p., 1955-1956.; 48 items. Typescript (some carbon) and printed items. (Box 12, Folder 9)
        Material consists of correspondence, a typescript article, and ephemera, arranged chronologically.
      - Victorianism. Material includes various holograph and typescript items, mostly notes, and miscellaneous ephemera, re aspects of victorianism. v.p., v.d.; 30 items. (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Manuscripts
  - Articles
    - Advertisements written at different times in his life, for commercial purposes. n.p., n.d.; 31 leaves. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 13, Folder 1)
      The subjects covered include cigarettes, perfume and yeast.
    - --- Articles on various subjects written at various times in his life. v.p., v.d.; 28 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 13, Folder 2)
      The articles are alphabetically arranged by title within the folder.
      Articles include:
      - Captain of the tabloids. New York, 1927.; 6 leaves. Typescript, with pencil corrections. (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Included is 1 leaf of correspondence concerning the article.
        Not known if published.
      - Christus; photoplay founded on the poem by Fausto Salvatori, directed by Count Giulio Antamaria for Cines of Rome. Criterion theater, New York, 5 leaves. Typescript (carbon) with pencil corrections. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Class prohibition vs. government monopoly... Asheville, North Carolina, April 16, 1914.; 3 leaves. Typescript with ink corrections. This appears to have been a school paper of Kenneth Macgowan's. Also included is 1 newspaper clipping. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Clubby California. New York, 1930.; 13 leaves. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Included are 2 copies, 1 an earlier version, plus 1 leaf of correspondence about the article.
      - Germs I have met; the life-story of T. Bacillus. Asheville, North Carolina, n.d.; 30 leaves. Typescript and carbon. (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Included are 2 copies.
      - The marble tablet. Boston, Massachusetts, n.d.; 3 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Not known if published, but perhaps this was an article for the Boston Transcript, for in the title heading, that newspaper is noted.
      - The new pacificism. Boston, Massachusetts, n.d.; 4 leaves. Typescript with corrections. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - News papers. Asheville, North Carolina, n.d.; 15 leaves. Typescript with corrections. (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Included are 2 versions.
      - Picturesque America. New York, n.d.; 12 leaves. Typescript with many corrections. (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Included are 2 versions, the one that appears to be the earlier version, entitled The Picturesque Life.
      - [Proposed charter for the city of Santa Monica] n.p., n.d.; 4 leaves. Typescript and carbon. (Box 13, Folder 2)
        2 versions included.
        Not known if used or published.
      - [Radio commercials] Los Angeles, n.d.; 8 leaves. Typescript (some carbon) and notes. (Box 13, Folder 2)
        This appears to be both an article on commercials and actual commercials, used on Extra News, Los Angeles.
      - Try this on your memory. n.p., n.d.; 11 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Included are 2 copies, 1 clipping, and a fragment of a musical score.
    - --- The fairv cross. New York, 1932.; 90 leaves. Typescript and carbon. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Included are 3 copies of the work, 2 versions, 1 version with extensive pencil corrections, and 1 final version plus carbon copy.
      Also included are 3 letters concerning the story.
    - --- Studies on love and marriage, compiled by Kenneth Macgowan and George V. Hamilton. New York, 1951.; 3 items. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Included are 3 different studies:
      - How I would make my husband over - as told by one hundred women.., 20 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Mothers and wives - how 100 men compare the loved ones of boyhood and manhood.., 13 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Untitled article on marriage., 10 leaves. Typescript. (Box 13, Folder 4)
        Also included with the material is 1 letter concerning the above listed studies.
        It appears likely that these studies were later incorporated into a book by the joint authors, What's Wrong With My Marriage.
    - --- Outline and research material for What's Wrong With My Marriage. n.p., 1951.; 13 leaves. Typescript, with corrections. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - --- Articles on motion pictures and television written at various times during Mr. Macgowan's life. v.p., v.d.; 21 items. Typescript (some carbon). The articles are alphabetically arranged by title within the folder. (Box 13, Folder 6)